<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Outlier Blog</title>
    <link>https://outlierblog.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Outlier Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 12:36:24 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlierblog.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Monte Carlo Method</title>
      <link>https://outlierblog.me/posts/monte_carlo_method/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 12:36:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlierblog.me/posts/monte_carlo_method/</guid>
      <description>The Monte Carlo method represents a reinforcement learning technique used to estimate the value of a state or state-action pair by averaging the returns achieved from those states or state-actions. Unlike traditional methods that rely on iterative updates, Monte Carlo methods learn from complete episodes, making them well-suited for tasks with a defined endpoint. These methods accumulate knowledge from experience, collecting sequences of states, actions, and rewards from real or simulated interactions with an environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Armed Bandit Problem and Its Solutions</title>
      <link>https://outlierblog.me/posts/multibandits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 14:21:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlierblog.me/posts/multibandits/</guid>
      <description>In probability theory and decision-making under uncertainty, the multi-armed bandit problem presents a challenge where a limited set of resources must be wisely allocated among competing choices to maximize the expected gain. This is a classic reinforcement learning problem that exemplifies the exploration-exploitation tradeoff dilemma.
Imagine a gambler facing a row of slot machines (also called one-armed bandits). The gambler must make a series of decisions: which machines to play, how many times to play each machine, the order in which to play them, and whether to stick with the current machine or switch to another one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Concepts In (Deep) Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://outlierblog.me/posts/key_concepts_rl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlierblog.me/posts/key_concepts_rl/</guid>
      <description>Reinforcement Learning (RL) revolves around the interactions between an agent and its environment. The environment represents the world where the agent lives and takes action. At each step, the agent observes some information about the environment, makes decisions, and affects the environment through its actions.
The agent also receives rewards from the environment, which indicate how well it is doing. The agent&amp;rsquo;s ultimate goal is to maximize the total rewards it receives, called return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://outlierblog.me/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlierblog.me/projects/</guid>
      <description>These are all of my data science projects I&amp;#39;ve worked on or I&amp;#39;m currently working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
