<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data mining on Outlier Blog</title>
    <link>https://outlierblog.me/tags/data-mining/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data mining on Outlier Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 11:40:44 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://outlierblog.me/tags/data-mining/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Customer Segmentation using K-means Clustering in Python</title>
      <link>https://outlierblog.me/posts/customer_segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 11:40:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlierblog.me/posts/customer_segmentation/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this ever-evolving landscape of business and marketing, understanding customers has become more critical than ever before. The ability to unlock the secrets behind their preferences, behaviors, and needs holds the key to delivering personalized experiences and fostering long-lasting relationships. But how can we effectively make sense of a massive pool of customer data?
That&amp;rsquo;s where customer segmentation comes into play. It is a fundamental aspect of marketing that involves dividing customers into distinct groups or segments based on their shared characteristics, behaviors, or needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market Basket Analysis With Apriori Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://outlierblog.me/posts/market_basket_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 11:31:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://outlierblog.me/posts/market_basket_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Market Basket Analysis is a powerful data mining technique that enables businesses to gain insights into customer purchasing patterns. By analyzing large datasets, such as purchase history, businesses can reveal product groupings and customer preferences. This technique became even more accessible with the adoption of electronic point-of-sale (POS) systems, which made it easier to collect transactional data and analyze customer behavior.
Market Basket Analysis is especially useful in industries like retail, e-commerce, and grocery, where customer behavior is complex and influenced by various factors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
